Finding Aid for Linda Varonich papers, 1970-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Linda Varonich papers 1970-2009
Varonich, Linda.
3.5 linear feet
2009173 Aa 2
President of the National Organization for Women, Michigan Conference from 2001 to 2005; topical files relating to Michigan NOW, to the national office of the National Organization for Women, and to various women’s issues.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Linda Varonich (donor no. 10259 ) and came to the library in September 2009. Addition papers have been received.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Linda Varonich became a member of the National Organization for Women in 1974. She was the North Dallas (Texas) NOW chapter president and served as the Legislative Vice-President of Texas NOW from 1983 to 1986. She became involved in the Oakland County (Mich.) NOW chapter in 1995 and served as the president of that chapter from 1998 to 2000. Varonich was the Legislative Vice-President of Michigan NOW from 1997 to 2001 before becoming the president of Michigan NOW where she served from 2001 to 2005. She was elected to represent the Great Lakes Region on the National NOW Board in 2006.
Varonich was also involved in the Women-Friendly Workplace Campaign and helped to organize the 2004 March for Women's Lives.
The papers of Linda Varonich document her activities in Michigan NOW. The papers of Linda Varonich document her activities in Michigan NOW. The collection is arranged alphabetically in two series: National Organization for Women (NOW) and Topical Files.
Subjects:
Feminists--Michigan.; National Organization for Women. Michigan Conference.; Varonich, Linda.; Women's rights--Michigan.
- National Organization for Women (NOW)
  The National Organization for Women (NOW) series documents Varonich's activities within the organization. This series contains materials from Michigan NOW as well as documents from the national group. Materials include newsletters, leadership lists, financial information and information on state conferences, the political action committee (PAC) and the state coordinating council. Additional documents relating to various issues can be found in the Topical Files series.
  - Board
    - Agendas 2003-2008 (Box 1)
    - Board member survey 2006, 2008 (Box 1)
    - Memos 2002, 2005-2008 (Box 1)
    - Minutes 2000-2008 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Bylaws 2000-2005 (scattered), undated (Box 1)
  - Chapter organizing and development 2000-2002, undated (Box 1)
  - Committee reports 2006-2008 (Box 1)
  - Contacts lists 2006-2008, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Chapter and state leaders 2001-2007 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 2001-2009 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Feminist Leadership (Box 1)
  - Fundraising 2001-2006 (scattered), undated (Box 1)
  - Intrepid Awards galas 2006, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Michigan NOW
    - Annual report information 2000-2004 (Box 1)
    - Executive Board 1999-2003, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Financial information
      - 1998-2007 (Box 1)
      - 2000-2009 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Great Lakes Region 2003-2004, 2006 undated (Box 1)
    - Great Lakes Regional Conference 2004, 2006, 2008 (Box 1)
    - Leadership lists 1998-2006 (Box 1)
    - Legislative agendas 2001-2004 (Box 1)
    - Legislative reports 1999, 2001, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Macomb County Chapter 2002, 2004, 2006 undated (Box 1)
    - Membership information 2000, 2002, 2004-2005 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous legislative materials 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Newsletters
      - 1998-2008 (scattered) (Box 1)
      - Grand Rapids area 2000, 2002 (Box 1)
      - Macomb County 2000-2005 (scattered) (Box 1)
      - Oakland County 1997-2007 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Oakland County Chapter 1970-2007 (scattered), undated (Box 1)
    - Policies and guidelines 1986 undated (Box 1)
    - Public Relations Guide 1992 (Box 1)
    - Political Action Committee 2000-2006 (scattered), undated (Box 1)
    - Public relations guide 1992 (Box 1)
    - State Conferences
      - 1995, 1997, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
      - 2001-2003 (Box 1)
      - 2004-2007, undated (Box 1)
    - State Coordinating Council (SCC) 1999-2003, 2005-2006 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1999-2006 (scattered), undated (Box 1)
  - National conferences 2002-2009 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - National Conference Resolutions 2002 (Box 2)
  - National NOW 2007 Conference Planning Committee, 2007 (Box 2)
  - NOW Foundation (Box 2)
  - "NOW is the Time" (Box 2)
  - "Passion for Justice" workbook and video 2002 (Box 2)
  - Political Organizing Manual (Box 2)
  - Regional elections information 2004 (Box 2)
  - Resolutions 2005-2008, undated (Box 2)
  - State officer report for Michigan 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Training manual 2002 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series includes a variety of materials, such as correspondence, a diary, flyers, pamphlets, campaign materials, legislative updates and manuals. This series also contains NOW documents such as bulletins, presentations, statements and toolkits that relate to various topics.
  - Act for Now newsletters 2005 (Box 2)
  - Abortion 1998-2002 (Box 2)
  - Affirmative action 2004-2006, undated (Box 2)
  - Building Opportunities Bonus (BOB) Coalition Action Packet 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Calendars 1994-2007 (scattered) (Box 2)
  - Campaign Finance Talk 2000, 2002-2003, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Campaign materials
    - Varonich 1999-2006 (scattered) (Box 2)
    - NOW members 2004 undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1998-2006 (scattered) (Box 2)
  - Child care and parental leave 1988-2004 (scattered) (Box 2)
  - Child custody cases 1993-2002 (scattered) (Box 2)
  - Clippings
    - Varonich 1987-1988, 1997, 2006 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1995-2008 (scattered) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - 1982, 1998-2002 (Box 2)
    - 2003-2006 (Box 2)
    - Undated (Box 2)
  - Diary 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Diversity 2006-2007 (Box 3)
  - Domestic and sexual violence 2007-2008, undated (Box 3)
  - Domestic workers 2007 undated (Box 3)
  - Equal marriage 2004 undated (Box 3)
  - Equal Rights Amendment (ERA) 2000, 2005 undated (Box 3)
  - Equality Begins at Home 1999 (Box 3)
  - Events 2005-2008 (scattered) (Box 3)
  - Faith and Feminism Workshop 2006 (Box 3)
  - Family and medical leave 1987 undated (Box 3)
  - Father for Equal Rights 2002 (Box 3)
  - Feminism 2008 undated (Box 3)
  - Flyers 2000-2007 (scattered), undated (Box 3)
  - Granholm, Jennifer 1998-1999, 2002-2006, undated (Box 3)
  - Handwritten notes 1998-2006 (scattered), undated (Box 3)
  - Health 2006-2007, undated (Box 3)
  - House and Senate Bills and related information 1999-2006, undated (Box 3)
  - Immigration
    - National Coalition for Immigrant Women's Rights 2007-2008 (Box 3)
    - NOW bulletins 2008 undated (Box 3)
    - Clippings 2008 (Box 3)
  - Institute for Women's Policy Research 2006, 2008 undated (Box 3)
  - International women's rights 2005, 2007 undated (Box 3)
  - Legal Momentum (women's rights group) 2005-2007 (Box 3)
  - Legislative updates 1999-2006 (Box 3)
  - March for Election Reform 2001 (Box 3)
  - March for Women's Lives 2004 (Box 3)
  - Media (Box 3)
  - Media Relations Workshop 1999 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Roundtable for Diversity and Inclusion 2007 (Box 3)
  - "Michigan Women" newsletter 1998-2008 (scattered) (Box 3)
  - Michigan Women's Commission 2005-2006 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Women's Summit 2005-2006 (Box 3)
  - Money, Organization and Media Workshop 2000 (Box 3)
  - NARAL (National Association for the Repeal of Abortion Laws) 1999 Midwest Regional Organizing Training, 1999 (Box 3)
  - NARAL (National Association for the Repeal of Abortion Laws) and MARAL (Michigan Association for the Repeal of Abortion Laws) 1999-2000, 2004-2005, undated (Box 3)
  - National Women's Law Center 2008 (Box 3)
  - Oakland County Democratic Party 1998-2006 (scattered), undated (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets
    - 1995-2005 (scattered) (Box 3)
    - Undated (Box 3)
  - Pay equity
    - 1984-2006 (scattered), undated (Box 3)
    - 2004-2007 (scattered), undated (Box 3)
  - Personal 1995, 2005 undated (Box 3)
  - Planned Parenthood 1998-2004 (scattered), undated (Box 3)
  - Photographs 2003 undated (Box 3)
  - Political 2002-2008 (scattered) (Box 3)
  - Reproductive rights 1997-2008 (Box 4)
  - Resolutions 1978-2005 (scattered), undated (Box 4)
  - Retirement 2008-2009, undated (Box 4)
  - School District of the City of Pontiac board goals 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Sexual harassment 2000-2002, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Single sex schools 1995-2008 (scattered), undated (Box 4)
  - Social security 1998-2005 (scattered), undated (Box 4)
  - "Title IX at 35" executive summary 2008 (Box 4)
  - United Automobile Workers (UWA) 1994, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (Box 4)
  - "Woman-to-Woman Voter Turnout" manual 2008 (Box 4)
  - Women of Color and Allies Summit 2005-2006 (Box 4)
  - Women-Friendly Workplace Campaign and Walmart 2003-2005, undated (Box 4)
  - Women's Equality Day 2001, 2004-2005 (Box 4)
  - Women's groups 1999-2006 (scattered), undated (Box 4)
  - Women's Policy, Inc. 2006, 2008 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1998-2006 (scattered), undated (Box 4)
    - 2002-2008 (scattered), undated (Box 4)